RODO NGUYEN

SUMMARY

Fullstack Software Engineer with rich skillset and experience in developing commercial applications. My focus has been on delivering efficient, high-quality products . In addition, I posssess strong collaborative skill and deep understanding of the business aspects. An avid learner.

My technical stack consists of JavaScript, Python, C# for backend and JavaScript for frontend.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript/TypeScript • C# • Python • SQL **Front-End**: React • Tailwind • Vite • HTML5 • CSS • SCSS **Back-End**: NestJS • ExpressJS

Database:PostgreSQL • MySQL • DynamoDB • MongoDBTesting:Jest • K6DevOps:Amazon AWS • Docker • Linux/Ubuntu • GitHub ActionsOthers:Git/GitHub

Soft Skills: Teamwork • Project management • Stakeholder engagement • Agile

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | DLTx Labs

Nov 2023 - Present

React • Nest.JS • Vite • Tailwind • PostgreSQL • .NET • Docker • Linux • GitHub Actions • K6

Cryptocurrency Exchange TCIA

- Implemented various core features across the REST API, User Interfaces and Database.
- Optimised Postgres database using advanced features (Views, Indexing), reducing execution time by x2 to x10.
- Was recognised by my implementation of foundational UI components that provide a unified and modern look product-wide. My code pattern facilitates customisability and resuability in this large-scale application, subsequently reducing developer's time and saving business's capital.
- Enhanced trade validation, trade execution and error handling, significantly improving application reliability which is detrimental to a crypto exchange.

Get Paid In Bitcoin (GPIB) | github.com/dltxio/v2.getpaidinbitcoin.com.au

- Led the maintenance of GPIB's both User and Admin portals.
- Upgraded the legacy User Interface to version 2, improving the usage experience of thousands of users on the app. This includes enhancing component functionalities, removing deprecated and updating core dependencies.
- Implemented the Bills page, allowing thousands of users to start paying bills with Bitcoin directly. This involves building new payment UI components and expanding the .NET API to interact with the database, authenticate, integrate with email provider's API.
- Engaged in meetings and showcases with the client. Worked closely with the client to define ticket and plan sprint.

Junior Software Engineer | AerVision Technologies

June 2023 - Nov 2023

React • .NET • Django

- Maintained and built new features for company product's frontend and backend.
- Swiftly addressed support tickets and liased with other team members when needed.

Software Engineer | S23M

Feb 2022 - Nov 2022

• Developed a new React application with a modern look using MaterialUI and integrated fully with the backend's REST API while collaborating closely with clients to gather product requirements.

PROJECTS

Community LLM Assistant | Bifrost Lab | github.com/bifrostlab/llm-assistant

2024

- Developed an LLM Assistant for a Community Discord Server VAIT (Vietnamese Aussies in IT) with built-in features to assist with general questions about the community, review members' resumes and more.
- Collaborated with a team of 2 Al Researchers, 1 Software Engineer and 1 DevOps Engineer to design and implement the project.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Technology (Computer Science) | Queensland University of Technology $6.4/7.0 \sim 91\% 2022$

- Exceled in Web/Cloud Computing, Machine Learning, Data Structures and Algorithms
- Received International Merit Scholarship (for High Performing Students) and Dean's List Award (for High GPA)